<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arian's blog</title><link>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Arian's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://arian-d.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A mediocre pseudo-espresso recipe with the AeroPress</title><link>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/aeropress-recipe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/aeropress-recipe/</guid><description>A real espresso requires an espresso machine, and that&amp;rsquo;s somewhat inconvenient for an average Joe like me, because
I can&amp;rsquo;t afford one. I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to spend that much money, if I could afford one. If I was willing to buy one and could afford it, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t wanna bring it to the office, since I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to use it at home. So, what can I do? I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to pay someone to make it for me at Starbucks, because it&amp;rsquo;s pricey and has never tasted good (to me).</description></item><item><title>AI on a laptop</title><link>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/ai-on-a-laptop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/ai-on-a-laptop/</guid><description>The AI craze is going strong. You would think it&amp;rsquo;d be over by now, but big boy companies keep throwing their money at Nvidia GPUs and overpriced LLM subscriptions.
For the average Joe, GPT4 and GPT4o are more than enough to do your day-to-day tasks or if you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, you can just have OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s API do everything you&amp;rsquo;re too lazy to do. This all comes at a cost:
Data privacy Are you okay sending your or your company&amp;rsquo;s data to OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s servers, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t use it to train their future model?</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Little Operator</title><link>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/my-favorite-little-operator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/my-favorite-little-operator/</guid><description>Sometimes, there are little things that solve so much that we take for granted. There&amp;rsquo;s also things that solve so much that aren&amp;rsquo;t used as often.
Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been relying on ??, which is a very interesting operator called &amp;ldquo;null-coalescing operator&amp;rdquo;. A fairly seasoned programmer probably uses it very often and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t find this as fascinating as I did, but for me, it&amp;rsquo;s a game-changer.
Take this for instance:
const somevar = null; if (somevar === null) { console.</description></item><item><title>Ngrok SystemD Service</title><link>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/ngrok-systemd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/ngrok-systemd/</guid><description>This is going to be a quick post, but it&amp;rsquo;s still something that I like. I love systemd, and try to (over)use it every time I can.
This is one of those use-cases where I can use ngrok to freely demo my app without having to set up a cloud instance or open up a port in my router. The simple usage of running ngrok is fine for simple cases like hosting a minecraft server for an hour, but if you need to run it in the background you&amp;rsquo;d need a service.</description></item><item><title>Steam Deck: The Linux User's Dream</title><link>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/steam-deck/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/steam-deck/</guid><description>When I received my Steam Deck about -checks Steam account- 3 months ago, I was already aware of what it was capable of, considering that I had been browsing r/SteamDeck while waiting for it. What I did not know was its capabilities as a Linux desktop or even server.
You may ask &amp;ldquo;what is so special about another Switch clone?&amp;rdquo; if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is, and if you do you may ask &amp;ldquo;what is so special about a handheld pc?</description></item><item><title>My first post</title><link>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://arian-d.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Hi,
I frankly don&amp;rsquo;t know where to begin, but I am glad you somehow found your way here.
Why The entire reason behind me starting this was a braindump. You may share the same experience of gulping down a large amount of coffee, flexing your fingers, and browsing the web or frantically coding away at your mechanical keyboard.
Whatever it may be, many of those great days (and nights) ended up being wasted for not writing down what I did, learned, discovered, regretted, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>